Finding Aid for Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy Records 1953-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy Records 1953-1974
Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy.
Records of the Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy, Tucson, Arizona. Correspondence files of Robert R. McMath, Leo Goldberg, and Orren C. Mohler, reports, minutes, financial and budgetary materials, and technical reports relating to the development of AURA and its predecessor organization, the Advisory Panel for the National Astronomical Observatory, and concerning observatories at Kitt Peak, Arizona, and Cerro Tololo, Chile; also material concerning political developments in Chile; and photographs.
85580 Bn 2
16 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The records were donated in several accessions between 1969 and 1974 by Professor Orren Mohler (donor no. 4765 )
The record group is open for research.
The Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy (AURA) was formed in 1957 by eight universities, including the University of Michigan, for purposes of building and administering the national astronomical observatory. AURA now operates Kitt Peak National Observatory in Arizona, and Cerro Tololo Interamerican Observatory in Chile, under contract for the National Science Foundation (NSF).
In the early 1950's American astronomers saw the need for a cooperative observatory to increase observing opportunities on large telescopes. The Flagstaff Photoelectric Conference sponsored by NSF in September 1953, resulted in a request to NSF to appoint a committee to study the needs of astronomy in the United States. By January 1954, Robert R. McMath had assembled the Advisory Panel for the National Astronomical Observatory, and for the next three years the panel studied the problems of the organization and location of the national astronomical observatory.
By 1957 the Advisory Panel had decided on the form of the association that would operate the observatory, and AURA was organized to assume the responsibility of operating it. Shortly thereafter, Kitt Peak was chosen as the site of the observatory, and construction began on a series of telescopes, including the McMath Solar Telescope, the Mayall 4-Meter Telescope, and others.
In 1960 AURA began searching for a suitable observatory site in Chile with the purpose of developing the first large observatory in the Southern Hemisphere. As a result of this survey, the Cerro Tololo, Interamerican Observatory was established in 1963, and construction began on several large telescopes.
The history of AURA since that period has been one of steady growth and increased service to the astronomical community through the two observatories.
The AURA record group provides a record of an important aspect of the development of modern science, the growth of cooperative scientific associations, and the beginnings of government support for basic research in the post-war period. In addition, the records include much information related to the University of Michigan Astronomy Department and observatories, since several faculty members, including Robert R. McMath, Leo Goldberg, and Orren C. Mohler, have been involved in the growth of AURA. The record group also provides a detailed history of the development of AURA itself, and the observatories at Kitt Peak and at Cerro Tololo, where it touches on scientific and political developments in Chile during the 1960s and 1970s.
The AURA record group includes files collected by three University of Michigan Astronomy Department faculty members who were active in the organization. Robert R. McMath, chairman of the Advisory Panel for the National Astronomical Observatory, first President of AURA, and Chairman of the Board of AURA, was responsible for most of the material dated before his death in 1962. Leo Goldberg, a consultant to the Advisory Panel, is responsible for a correspondence file related to the work of the panel. This file partially duplicates McMath's correspondence file. On the death of McMath, Orren C. Mohler assumed the duties of University of Michigan representative on the AURA Board of Directors and continued to add to the record group. Some of the material dated before McMath's death and all material after that date was collected by Mohler.
The collection includes seven major types of records: historical/informational materials; correspondence; minutes/reports; governance records including papers of the board of directors and the executive committee; committee and subcommittee files; financial/funding records; files about the Kitt Peak and Cerro Tololo observatories; and miscellaneous which includes a few folders of photographs. Correspondence is divided into three groups according to the originators of the files. Within each group some correspondence is arranged chronologically and some by correspondent, but there is considerable overlap between the two sequences. Reports, minutes, and financial records are arranged chronologically.
Subjects:
Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy.; Astronomy--United States.; Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory.; Chile.; Kitt Peak National Observatory.; McMath Solar Telescope.; National Science Foundation (U.S.); University of Michigan. Dept. of Astronomy.; National Science Foundation (U.S.). Advisory Panel for the National Astronomical Observatory.; University of Michigan. Observatory.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy.; Astronomical observatories.; Astronomy.; Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory.; Kitt Peak National Observatory.; McMath Solar Telescope.; Portage Lake Observatory (University of Michigan)
Contributors:
Goldberg, Leo.; McMath, Robert R. (Robert Raynolds), 1891-1962.; Mohler, Orren, 1908-; Adams, Walter Sydney, 1876-1956.; Blanco, Victor Manuel.; Bowen, Ira Sprague, 1898-1973.; Brode, Robert B. (Robert Bigham), 1900-1986; Carmichael, Leonard, 1898-1973; Cisler, Walker L. (Walker Lee), 1897-1994; Dunham, Theodore J., 1897-; Edmondson, Frank K. (Frank Kelly), 1912-; Evans, John Wainwright, 1909-; Harvill, Richard Anderson, 1905-; Hayden, Carl Trumbull, 1877-1972.; Hiltner, W. A. (William Albert), 1914-; Irwin, John B.; Johnson, Harold L. (Harold Lester), 1921-1980.; Keller, Geoffrey, 1918-; Klopsteg, Paul E. (Paul Ernest), 1889-; Lee, Gilbert Lamont, 1919-; Mayall, N. U. (Nicholas Ulrich), 1906-1993; Meinel, Aden B.; Menzel, Donald H. (Donald Howard), 1901-1976; Miller, Freeman D. (Freeman Devold), 1909-2000; Pierce, Austin Keith, 1918-; Rabaut, Louis Charles, 1886-1961.; Röosch, Jean.; Seeger, Raymond John, 1906-; Shane, Charles Donald, 1895-1983; Shapley, Harlow, 1885-1972.; Skidmore, Owings and Merrill.; Ströomgren, Bengt, 1908-; Struve, Otto, 1897-1963.; Tuve, Merle Antony, 1901-1982.; Waterman, Alan Tower, 1892-1967; Whitford, Albert E. (Albert Edward), 1905-2002
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Historical/Informational
  - Articles of Incorporation and by-laws (Box 1)
  - Contracts (Box 1)
  - Lists of Board of Directors and Officers 1957-1973, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Historical materials (to 1959) (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence files (Robert R. McMath)
    - By date
      - January-June 1953 (Box 1)
      - July-December 1953 (Box 1)
      - 1954 (Box 1)
      - 1954 regarding National Astronomical Observatory (Box 1)
      - 1955 (Box 1)
      - 1955 regarding National Astronomical Observatory (Box 1)
      - 1956 (Box 1)
      - 1956 regarding National Astronomical Observatory (Box 1)
      - 1957 (Box 2)
      - 1957 regarding Formation and Organization of AURA (Box 2)
      - October 1957 (Box 2)
      - November 1957 (Box 2)
      - December 1957 (Box 2)
      - 1958, 2 volumes (Box 2)
      - January-July 1958 (Box 2)
      - August 1958 (Box 2)
      - September 1958 (Box 2)
      - October 1958 (Box 2)
      - November 1958 (Box 2)
      - December 1958 (Box 2)
      - January-February 1959 (Box 2)
      - March-April 1959 (Box 2)
      - May 1959 (Box 2)
      - June-July 1959 (Box 2)
      - August-September 1959 (Box 2)
      - October-December 1959 (Box 2)
      - January-February 1960 (Box 2)
      - March-April 1960 (Box 2)
      - May-June 1960 (Box 2)
      - July-August 1960 (Box 2)
      - September-October 1960 (Box 2)
      - November-December 1960 (Box 2)
      - January-March 1961 (Box 3)
      - April-June 1961 (Box 3)
      - July-September 1961 (Box 3)
      - October-December 1961 (Box 3)
    - By name
      - James E. Luton 1959-1961, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - N.U. Mayall 1960-1961, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - A.B. Meinel 1959-1961, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - James M. Miller 1959-1961, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Orren C. Mohler 1959 (Box 3)
      - Joseph Nunn 1956 (Box 3)
      - Ralph Patey 1959-1960, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - A. Keith Pierce 1961, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - C.D. Shane 1959-1961, 3 folders (Box 3)
      - Skidmore, Owings & Merrill 1959-1961, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence files (Leo Goldberg)
    - January-June 1955 (Box 4)
    - July-December 1955 (Box 4)
    - January-April 1956 (Box 4)
    - May-August-1956 (Box 4)
    - September-December 1956 (Box 4)
    - January-June 1957 (Box 4)
    - July-December 1957 (Box 4)
    - Joseph Nunn 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence files (Orren C. Mohler)
    - By date
      - 1958 (Box 4)
      - 1959 (Box 4)
      - 1960 (Box 4)
      - 1961 (Box 4)
      - January-June 1962 (Box 4)
      - July-December 1962 (Box 4)
      - January-June 1963 (Box 4)
      - July-December 1963 (Box 4)
      - 1964 (Box 4)
      - 1965 (Box 4)
      - January-June 1966 (Box 4)
      - July-December 1966 (Box 4)
      - January-May 1967 (Box 4)
      - June-December 1967 (Box 4)
      - 1968 (Box 4)
      - 1969 (Box 4)
      - 1970 (Box 4)
      - 1971 (Box 4)
      - 1972 (Box 4)
      - 1973 (Box 4)
      - 1974 (Box 4)
    - By name
      - D.L. Crawford 1966-1971 (Box 4)
      - Julia Elliott 1963-1971 (Box 4)
      - Leo Goldberg 1970-1972 (Box 4)
      - Arthur A. Hoag 1966-1971 (Box 4)
      - N.U. Mayall 1961-1971, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - James M. Miller 1961-1970 (Box 4)
      - A. Keith Pierce 1960-1972 (Box 4)
      - Nicholas Sanduleak 1966 (Box 4)
      - George Wallerstein 1969-1970 (Box 4)
      - A.E. Whitford 1970 (Box 4)
      - Rupert Wildt 1966-1970 (Box 4)
- Minutes/Reports
  - Weekly minutes
    - September-December 1958 (Box 5)
    - January-March 1959 (Box 5)
  - Monthly reports
    - April-July 1959 (Box 5)
    - August-November 1959 (Box 5)
    - December 1959-March 1960 (Box 5)
    - April-August 1960 (Box 5)
    - September-December 1960 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1961 (Box 5)
    - May-August 1961 (Box 5)
    - September-December 1961 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1962 (Box 5)
    - May-August 1962 (Box 5)
    - September-December 1962 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1963 (Box 5)
    - May-December 1963 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1964 (Box 5)
    - May-August 1964 (Box 5)
    - September-December 1964 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1965 (Box 5)
    - May-August 1965 (Box 5)
    - September-December 1965 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1966 (Box 5)
  - Bimonthly reports
    - May-August 1966 (Box 5)
    - September-December 1966 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1967 (Box 5)
    - May-August 1967 (Box 5)
    - September-December 1967 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1968 (Box 5)
    - May-August 1968 (Box 5)
    - September-December 1968 (Box 5)
    - January-April 1969 (Box 6)
    - May-August 1969 (Box 6)
    - September-December 1969 (Box 6)
  - Quarterly reports
    - January-March 1970 (Box 6)
    - April-June 1970 (Box 6)
    - July-September 1970 (Box 6)
    - October-December 1970 (Box 6)
    - January-March 1971 (Box 6)
    - April-June 1971 (Box 6)
    - July-September 1971 (Box 6)
    - October-December 1971 (Box 6)
    - January-March 1972 (Box 6)
    - April-June 1972 (Box 6)
    - July-September 1972 (Box 6)
    - October-December 1972 (Box 6)
    - January-March 1973 (Box 6)
    - April-June 1973 (Box 6)
    - July-September 1973 (Box 6)
    - January-March 1974 (Box 6)
  - Annual/Biennial Report
    - 1961-1962 (Box 6)
    - 1963-1965 (biennial) (Box 6)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 6)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 6)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 6)
    - 1968-1970 (biennial) (Box 6)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 6)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 6)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 6)
- Governance Records
  - Establishing Materials
    - Flagstaff Photoelectric Conference 1953 Condensed papers (Box 6)
    - NAO Advisory Panel 1956-1957 Minutes (Box 6)
  - Board of Directors Papers and Minutes
    - 1957-1958 (Box 6)
    - 1959 (Box 6)
    - 1960 (Box 7)
    - 1961, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - 1962 (Box 7)
    - 1963 (Box 7)
    - 1964 (Box 7)
    - 1965 (Box 7)
    - 1966 (Box 7)
    - 1966 regarding Carnegie Institution of Washington (Box 7)
    - 1967 (Box 7)
    - 1968 (Box 7)
    - 1969 (Box 7)
    - 1970 (Box 7)
    - 1971 (Box 7)
    - 1972 (Box 7)
    - 1973 (Box 7)
    - 1974 (Box 7)
  - Executive Committee, Papers and Minutes
    - 1958-1959 (Box 7)
    - 1960 (Box 7)
    - 1961 (Box 7)
    - 1962, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - 1963, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - 1964, 3 folders (Box 7)
    - 1965 (Box 8)
    - 1966 (Box 8)
    - 1967 (Box 8)
    - 1968 (Box 8)
    - 1969, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 1970, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 1971, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - 1972, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - 1973 (Box 8)
- Committees/Subcommittees
  - Scientific Committee (papers and minutes)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 8)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 8)
    - 1962 (Box 8)
    - 1963 (Box 9)
    - 1964 (Box 9)
    - 1965, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - 1966 (Box 9)
    - 1967, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1968 (Box 9)
    - 1969 (Box 9)
    - 1970 (Box 9)
    - 1971, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1972, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1973 (Box 9)
  - Scientific Committee (Personnel reports from Observatory Director)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 9)
    - 1964 (Box 9)
    - 1965, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1966, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1967, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - 1968, 3 folders (Box 9)
    - 1969 (Box 9)
    - 1970-1972 (Box 9)
    - 1973 (Box 9)
  - Planetary Sciences Subcommittee
    - 1969 (Box 9)
    - 1970 (Box 9)
    - 1971 (Box 9)
  - Solar Astronomy Subcommittee (papers and minutes)
    - 1964 (Box 10)
    - 1965 (Box 10)
    - 1966 (Box 10)
    - 1967 (Box 10)
    - 1968 (Box 10)
    - 1969 (Box 10)
    - 1970 (Box 10)
    - 1971 (Box 10)
  - Space Astronomy Subcommittee and Orbiting Telescope Project
    - 1959-1960 (Box 10)
    - 1961, 3 volumes (Box 10)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 10)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 10)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 10)
  - Stellar Astronomy Subcommittee
    - 1962-1963 (Box 10)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 10)
    - 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - 1968 (Box 10)
    - 1969 (Box 10)
    - 1970 (Box 10)
    - 1971 (Box 10)
    - 1972 (Box 10)
  - Chile Subcommittee
    - 1965 (Box 10)
    - 1966 (Box 10)
    - 1967 (Box 10)
    - 1968 (Box 10)
    - 1969 (Box 10)
    - 1970 (Box 10)
    - 1971 (Box 10)
    - 1973 (Box 10)
  - Organization Committee
    - 1967-1968 (Box 11)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 11)
    - 1971, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - 1972 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous committees
    - Audit Committee 1964-1965 (Box 11)
    - Cerro Tololo Administrative Meetings 1966-1967 (Box 11)
    - Consulting Policy, Special Committee on 1961 (Box 11)
    - Grating Conference 1970 (Box 11)
    - Instrumentation, Subcommittee on 1963-1967 (Box 11)
    - Long Range Needs, Ad Hoc Committee on 1967-1968 (Box 11)
    - Nominating Committees 1962-1972, 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Observatory Technical Services, Ad Hoc Committee on 1969 (Box 11)
    - Research Support Division 1970 (Box 11)
    - Salary Scales, Committee on 1959-1971 (Box 11)
    - Scientific Staff Meeting 1970 (Box 11)
    - Telescope Committee 1959-1965 (Box 11)
    - Users Committee 1972 (Box 11)
    - Visiting Committee 1972 (Box 11)
- Financial/Funding
  - AURA--National Science Foundation Meetings
    - 1960 (Box 11)
    - 1962 (Box 11)
  - Accountants' Report, Financial Statements
    - 1958-1959 (Box 11)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 11)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 11)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 11)
    - 1967-1969 (Box 11)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 11)
    - 1972-1973 (Box 11)
  - Comptroller General's Report to Congress 1967 (Box 11)
  - National Science Foundation Contract Financial Report
    - Contract G-2622 Solar Project 1957-1959 (Box 11)
    - Contract C-63- 1960-1968 (Box 11)
    - Contract C-270 1963 (Box 11)
    - Contract C-300 1965-1968 (Box 11)
    - Contract C-400 1970-1972 (Box 11)
    - Contract C-525 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Budgets, Financial Plans, Financial Reports 1956-1979
    - Fiscal Year 1956-Fiscal Year 1965 (Box 12)
    - Fiscal Year 1966-Fiscal Year 1976 (Box 13)
  - Five Year Budget Plan
    - Fiscal Year 1968-Fiscal Year 1972 (Box 14)
    - Fiscal Year 1969-Fiscal Year 1973 (Box 14)
    - Fiscal Year 1971-Fiscal Year 1975 (Box 14)
    - Fiscal Year 1972-Fiscal Year 1976 (Box 14)
    - Fiscal Year 1973-Fiscal Year 1977 (Box 14)
    - Fiscal Year 1974-Fiscal Year 1978 (Box 14)
    - Fiscal Year 1975-Fiscal Year 1979 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Financial Documents (Box 14)
- Observatories
  - Kitt Peak National Observatory Policy Manual 1961, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Director's Report, Kitt Peak National Observatory
    - 1962-1964 (Box 14)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 14)
    - 1969-1972 (Box 14)
  - Director's Report, Cerro Tololo Interamerican Observatory 1964-1971 (Box 14)
  - Technical Reports and Plans
    - National Astronomical Observatory Advisory Panel, 4 volumes; 1 folders (Box 14)
    - Kitt Peak Solar Telescope, 2 volumes (Box 14)
    - Kitt Peak Solar Telescope, 10 volumes (Box 15)
    - Kitt Peak Solar Telescope, Bids and Bidders list (Box 15)
    - Kitt Peak Solar Telescope, Blueprints, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Kitt Peak Solar Telescope, Dedication 1962 (Box 15)
    - Kitt Peak 150" Telescope, 1 volumes (Box 15)
    - Kitt Peak 150" Telescope, Design Precepts (Box 15)
    - Kitt Peak 150" Telescope, Blueprints (Box 15)
    - Kitt Peak 150" Telescope, Dedication 1973 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous Telescopes and Projects, 1 volumes (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous Telescopes and Projects, 4 volumes; 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous Blueprints (Box 16)
    - Cerro Tololo Construction Data (Box 16)
    - Cerro Tololo Dedication 1967 (Box 16)
    - Carnegie Southern Observatory, 2 volumes; 1 folders (Box 16)
    - European Southern Observatory (Box 16)
    - Associated Universities, Inc., Organization and objectives (Box 16)
- Miscellaneous
  - Proposals to National Science Foundation
    - 1954-1956 (Box 16)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 16)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 16)
  - AURA Open Door Policy 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - Newsclippings and Press Releases, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Photographs
    - AURA board and dedication March 15, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Cerro Tololo Inter-American Observatory (Box 16)
    - Curtis Schmidt telescope removal from University of Michigan Portage Lake Observatory 1967 (Box 16)
    - Kitt Peak National Observatory
      - Buildings and observatory (Box 16)
      - Construction, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - Equipment and personnel (Box 16)
      - Site, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Research photos (Box 16)
Selective Index of Robert R. McMath Correspondence (Boxes 1-3)
Adams, Walter Sydney, 1876-1956
Aug. 23, 1954 (NAO)
Bowen, Ira Sprague, 1898-
Throughout
Brode, Robert B., 1900-
Nov. 18, 1958 (loose)
Carmichael, Leonard, 1898-
Oct. 26, 1954; Oct. 18, 1954; Nov. 23, 1954 (NAO)
Dunham, Theodore J., 1897-
July 30, 1954; Aug. 11, 1954 (NAO) June 1, 1955; July 20, 1955; July 14, 1955; July 23, 1955; July 27, 1955 (NAO)
Edmondson, Frank K., 1912-
Throughout
Evans, John Wainwright, 1909-
Aug. 18, 1959
Goldberg, Leo, 1913-
Throughout and Alphabetical file
Harvill, Richard Anderson, 1905-
Feb. 14, 1955; Feb. 24, 1955; and Mar. 7, 1955 (NAO), Mar. 15, 1958; and Apr. 24, 1958 (AURA), Dec. 20, 1958; and Dec. 2, 1958 (loose), Jan. 2, 1959; Mar. 6, 1959; Nov. 24, 1959; Nov. 23, 1959; Nov. 13, 1959; Nov. 4, 1959; and Dec. 10, 1959
Hayden, Carl Trumbull, 1877-
May 13, 1958; June 6, 1958; and July 23, 1958 (AURA)
Irwin, John B.
Jan. 6, 1954; June 10, 1954 (NSF); May 17, 1954 (NAO); Dec. 4, 1955 (NAO)
Johnson, Harold Lester, 1921-
Jan. 3, 1956; June 6, 1956; Sept. 6, 1956 (NAO); Aug. 6, 1957; Aug. 23, 1957; Aug. 25, 1957; Oct. 11, 1957; Oct. 12, 1957; Oct. 29, 1957 (AURA)
Keller, Geoffrey, 1918-
Throughout
Klopsteg, Paul Ernest, 1889-
Mar. 10, 1954 (NSF); Sept. 16, 1958 (loose); Mar. 31, 1960
Lee, Gilbert Lamont, 1919-
Throughout
Mayall, Nicholas Ulrich, 1906-
Dec. 23, 1957 (loose); June 16, 1961; and alphabetical file
Meinel, Aden B.
Throughout and alphabetical file
Menzel, Donald Howard, 1901-
Throughout
Mohler, Orren Cuthbert, 1908-
Mar. 27, 1956; and Nov. 12, 1956 (NAO); Feb. 6, 1957; and Aug. 29, 1957 (AURA); Nov. 23.1957; and Nov. 30, 1957 (loose); Mar. 7, 1959; May 27, 1959; and alphabetical file
Pierce, Austin Keith
Throughout and alphabetical file
Rabaut, Louis Charles, 1886-
June 12, 1958; May 26, 1958 (AURA)
Röosch, Jean
Apr. 13, 1956; and Apr. 4, 1956 (NAO)
Seeger, Raymond John, 1906-
Throughout
Shane, Charles Donald, 1895-
Throughout and alphabetical file
Shapley, Harlow, 1885-1972
Apr. 21, 1953
Skidmore, Owings and Merrill (architectural firm)
In alphabetical file
Ströomgren, Bengt Georg Daniel, 1908-
Throughout
Struve, Otto, 1898-1963
Throughout
Tuve, Merle Antony, 1901-
Oct. 5, 1954; and Oct. 6, 1954 (NAO)
Waterman, Alan Tower, 1892-
Throughout
Whitford, Albert Edward, 1905-
Throughout
Selective Index to Leo Goldberg Correspondents (Box 4)
Edmondson, Frank K, 1912-
Apr. 11, 1957
Johnson, Harold Lester, 1921-
May 19, 1956; May 14, 1956; June 17, 1956
McMath, Robert Raynolds, 1891-1962.
Throughout
Meinel, Aden B.
Throughout
Waterman, Alan Tower, 1892-
Mar. 24, 1955
Orren C. Mohler Correspondents (Box 4)
Blanco, Victor M.
Throughout
Boven, Ira Sprague, 1898-
Apr. 11, 1963
Cisler, Walker Lee, 1897-
June 23, 1962
Edmondson, Frank K., 1912-
Dec. 11, 1959; Oct. 6, 1961; June 6, 1962; May 29, 1963; Oct. 25, 1963; Nov. 26, 1963; Sept. 3, 1968; Feb. 8, 1974
Goldberg, Leo, 1913-
In alphabetical file
Harvill, Richard Anderson, 1905-
May 8, 1963; Apr. 22, 1968
Hiltner, William Albert, 1914-
Throughout
Lee, Gilbert Lamont, 1919-
Feb. 7, 1962; Apr. 11, 1973; July 20, 1973; May 15, 1973; May 9, 1973; May 10, 1973; June 29, 1973; Sept. 6, 1973; Oct. 24, 1973; Oct. 1, 1973; Nov. 21, 1973
Mayall, Nicholas Ulrich, 1906-
Throughout and alphabetical file
Meinel, Aden B.
Throughout
Menzel, Donald Howard, 1901-
May 22, 1963
Miller, Freeman Devold, 1909-
Throughout
Pierce, A. Kieth
Throughout and alphabetical file
Shane, Charles Donald, 1895-
Nov. 6, 1958; Feb. 6, 1962
Whitford, Albert Edward, 1905-
In alphabetical file